<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Floating Continent</title>
    <link>https://thefloatingcontinent.com</link>
    <atom:link href="https://thefloatingcontinent.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>The personal website and blog of Alexander Petros</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 18:12:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>The Easiest Moment in Human History to Plan a Party</title>
      <link>https://thefloatingcontinent.com/blog/death-of-the-social-network</link>
      <guid>https://thefloatingcontinent.com/blog/death-of-the-social-network</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <content type="html"><link rel="stylesheet" href="/resources/css/common.css"> <link rel="stylesheet" href="/resources/css/blog.css"> <article> <h1>The Easiest Moment in Human History to Plan a Party</h1> <p class=pubdate><time datetime="2022-11-04">November 4, 2022</time>  <p> Do you remember Facebook Graph Search?  <p> In 2013, Facebook <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/1/15/3878950/facebook-announces-graph-search">announced a new feature</a> that it touted as a bold and revolutionary new way to search the web. It was called Graph Search, and it would index a powerful dataset that Google could never access: your social graph. By taking advantage of Facebook’s incomparable knowledge of who you are and who you know, Graph Search could help you search not just the web, but also your own life. It launched with a handful of classic Web 2.0 promises like “when you’re in a new city, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/1/15/3880004/facebook-graph-search-hands-on">you can search up which restaurants your friends liked</a>.”  <p> Graph Search is dead now—essentially <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook_Graph_Search">killed in 2019</a>—and so are social networks. What we have instead is “social media,” a term often used interchangeably with “social network,” but different in critical ways. As a society, we haven’t really reckoned with the death of social networks—the names of the platforms haven’t changed and our networks still live there, so why would we? But the way we use Facebook, Instagram, and the rest has changed drastically, and the way we feel about them has changed even more.  <figure>   <img src="/resources/blog/zuckerberg-we-run-ads.png"        alt="A side-by-side cable news frame with Orrin Hatch on the left and Mark Zuckerberg on the right. Zuckerbeg is smiling and Hatch is not.">   <figcaption>Mark Zuckerberg's big moment (via NBC News)</figcaption> </figure>  <p> <a href=https://thefloatingcontinent.com/blog/death-of-the-social-network>Continue Reading...</a> </content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unbearable Cheapness of AI-Generated Art</title>
      <link>https://thefloatingcontinent.com/blog/ai-art-generator-cheapness</link>
      <guid>https://thefloatingcontinent.com/blog/ai-art-generator-cheapness</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <content type="html"><link rel="stylesheet" href="/resources/css/common.css"> <link rel="stylesheet" href="/resources/css/blog.css"> <article> <h1>The Unbearable Cheapness of AI-Generated Art</h1> <p class=pubdate><time datetime="2022-09-16">September 16, 2022</time>  <p> As occasionally befalls internet culture writers, it was once again time for Charlie Warzel to write a piece about Alex Jones.  <p> The top photo for articles about figures like Alex Jones tend to coagulate into a few familiar poses. Yelling at the camera; yelling at the InfoWars desk; yelling on the street—you get the idea. These quickly become repetitive, so Warzel asked the Midjourney AI art generator to produce a different spin on the classic Jones image, and used the result to introduce <a href="https://newsletters.theatlantic.com/galaxy-brain/62f28a6bbcbd490021af2db4/where-does-alex-jones-go-from-here/">his article about Alex Jones' day in court.</a> This made a bunch of people angry, because it appeared to validate fears that machine learning models are about to replace illustrators in publications like <cite>The Atlantic</cite>, which purchased Warzel's newsletter last year.  <p> This is a reasonable fear. The technology that allows you to type a simple idea and have an algorithm conjure it into existence is miraculous. If businesses—particularly the notoriously stingy media businesses—can cut costs and keep the same level of quality, they will definitely do so. But I am skeptical that Midjourney is going to replace a lot of work for illustrators, precisely because it cannot produce that level of quality on its own.  <figure> <img style="max-height:400px" src="/resources/blog/alex-jones-ai-art-image.png" alt="A Midjourney-generated image of InfoWars host Alex Jones sitting alone at a desk, surrounded by newspapers."/> <figcaption>"Alex Jones inside an American Office under fluorescent lights" <br> (AI art by Midjourney, text prompt by Charlie Warzel)</figcaption> </figure>  <a href=https://thefloatingcontinent.com/blog/ai-art-generator-cheapness>Continue Reading...</a> </content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When the Down Arrow is not an Upside-Down Up Arrow</title>
      <link>https://thefloatingcontinent.com/blog/upside-down-arrow-unicode</link>
      <guid>https://thefloatingcontinent.com/blog/upside-down-arrow-unicode</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <content type="html"><link rel="stylesheet" href="/resources/css/common.css"> <link rel="stylesheet" href="/resources/css/blog.css"> <article>  <h1>When the Down Arrow is not an Upside-Down Up Arrow</h1> <p class=pubdate><time datetime="2022-05-25">May 25, 2022</time>  <p> First posts are hard, so I'll start small. Here's two arrows: <p> &#x21E7; &#x21E9;  <p> If you're on reading this on a relatively recent smartphone, chances are you see two reflected, but otherwise identical arrows. One points up and the other points down. On MacOS (Big Sur 11.6), however, the up arrow is much squatter than the one pointing down. This is a photo of how it renders on my MacBook Pro:  <figure> <img src="/resources/blog/two-arrows.png" alt="A screenshot of two arrows, a thick one pointing up, and a comparitively skinnier one pointing down."> </figure>  <p> Alex, those are two different arrows. Well yes, in the sense that one is up and the other is down, but they should be otherwise identical. I input two Unicode characters, "Upwards White Arrow" and "Downwards White Arrow", and I expected (reasonably, I think) that the down arrow would have the same proportions as the up arrow, only pointing down. So what's going on here? <a href=https://thefloatingcontinent.com/blog/upside-down-arrow-unicode>Continue Reading...</a> </content>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
